So, I've been playing around with Opus
5.5 and GBD6 Soul all day long, and I
just ran them across 10 different use
cases. I'm talking things like building
websites, editing videos, building slide
decks, browser use, tons of reasoning,
and then a few other things as well. So,
let's not waste any time and just get
straight into this video. Okay, so
before we start looking at all these
comparisons, I wanted to talk about the
pricing of these two models real quick.
So, Opus 5.5 on the left is double the
price of GBD6 Soul on the right. You can
see that Opus is four bucks for the
input and 20 bucks for the output,
whereas Soul is $2 and $10. Now, the
reason I wanted to bring this up is
because when I first glance at these
prices, my instinct is like, okay, well,
Opus is probably going to be a little
bit better than Soul. That's typically
just what you think when something's a
little bit more expensive. Now, I know a
lot of you guys might disagree with that
perspective, but the way that I like to
think about AI models is I like to think
about, okay, if I had a hundred bucks
and I gave a hundred bucks to Opus and I
gave a 100 bucks to Soul, which one
would give me a better output or better
quality for that 100 bucks? So, that's
why I think it's important to sort of
look at that metric and sort of, you
know, now I have a little bit of a
feeling of what I think these models
might be like, but obviously that's why
we run tests. So, anyways, now that we
got that out of the way, let's jump into
some examples. So, real quick before we
jump into the 10 use cases, I wanted to
do a real simple example just to show
you what they feel like and how they
think. So, on the left we have Soul and
on the right we have Opus and this is
the cloud desktop app and the Codex
desktop app. And I shut off this prompt
that says, "Pull in my two latest
Fireflies calls for Q4 planning and
ingest those transcripts into the wiki."
I spelled that wrong so hopefully it
knows what I meant. And I said, "Then
find me my last AIS Plus Q&A where I
brought up NAND." So these are two
different tasks. One is ingesting calls
into a wiki and one is finding
something. So, it'll be interesting to
see how they think about doing these in
parallel. The other thing is this isn't
super super simple. These two calls
combined is about 4 hours of transcript.
So, it has to create all those links and
the indexes and link everything
together. So, it's not super simple, but
I just want to see how these models feel
and how quick and lightweight they feel
as well. And you can see so far Soul
seems to be cooking way ahead of Opus
5.5. It's doing these both things in
parallel. Like I said, it's looking for
the new Fireflies calls and ingesting
them. And it's also locating the Q&A in
parallel. So this is pretty interesting.
It's been about 6 minutes now and Claude
came back and said, "Hey, I noticed that
something else is also doing this." So
it noticed Codex doing it and Codex so
far has the answer wrong about when I
last mentioned Nitn. It said August
17th. But the right answer is what Opus
found which was September 14th. So
anyways, I said overwrite. It's okay.
Both of these models are still spinning
and soul just finished as you can see
and it got this answer wrong. And that's
not good, right? Like it's not that hard
for a model to look through a bunch of
transcripts and find the most recent one
where Niden was mentioned. It's probably
because it was spelled out wrong like nn
or nadnen as you can see here when it
was actually transcribed. But still I
feel like that is a problem that soul
should have found for me and they
finished up in basically the same amount
of time but opus's answer here was
definitely better. So this very quick
experiment gives us a little bit of a
baseline to take into account as we head
into the next 10 actual use cases. So
let's jump right in. Okay, so the first
one was a quick website design. I gave
in all 10 of these examples I gave both
models the exact same prompt. So here is
one output. I won't tell you which one
this was yet. We have perk form. Your
morning shouldn't require two drinks. We
can see as we move our mouse, the keys
and the can and the background are on a
different layer. We start to scroll down
and we get this little animation right
here. You can see the layering come into
play. And now we have a different image
down here. Coffee in one hand, protein
in the other. Two purchases, two things
to carry, a shaker to rinse, blah blah
blah. Or we have pull the tab. I like
that little animation. That's kind of
cool. Um, we get some smoke coming out.
Your coffee and protein one can. We keep
scrolling down here. You have text
animations with all the text coming into
view. Pick your first can here. Okay, a
nice little rotation animation. I do
think that that's actually pretty clean.
And we come down here to some FAQ. And
then we have out the door. I'm not sure
if that's a glitch or it just leaves
frame really quick. But anyways, this
was one output. Let's take a look at the
other one right here. We can see if we
reload, we get your morning shouldn't
require two drinks. Not as strong of a
hero image right now, but we scroll in,
we start to get some different text
animations as well. we get like a little
opening a vault. We have a weird
packaging style image rather than like a
realistic looking image. So, I think
that was a bad design choice there. Um,
but you can see that both of these are
keeping the same sort of like narrative
and the same branding. We're getting all
the same sort of like text animations.
We're getting um once again the
packaging pictures rather than like real
product images, which I don't love. And
this overall, this one just seems a lot
more simple. Definitely not as premium
as this first one. So, this first one
was definitely the winner when it comes
to design and style. And this one was
Opus 5.5 and this one was GBT6 Soul.
Real quick guys, by the way, if you want
the skill that I use to generate scroll
driven and layered websites just like
these examples that you saw, then you
can grab this for completely free. The
link for that will be down in the
description. Let's get back to the
video. Now, when we take a look at the
pricing, we can see here they both took
about 35 minutes. Opus took a little
longer and Opus also cost three times as
much. So, $1832 compared to 5.89. But
right now, this one, even though with
the price, the winner of this experiment
is going to Opus 5.5. No doubt. So, 10
Opus 5.5. Okay. So, example number two
is something that I think is just a
really, really cool benchmark that I
might keep doing for all these models
where I basically give them this
Frame.io link with tons of different
videos, 100 gigabytes of videos from our
recent AIS Live event. And I basically
just ask them to create a sizzle reel, a
30-cond sizzle reel that helps us market
the next event, which is October 17th
and 18th. If you guys are interested,
definitely check it out. I'll put a link
to the event in the description. But
anyways, I basically want them to look
through everything, tell a story out of
it, and make a high energy sizzle reel.
So, let's take a look at both outputs.
This first one will be Opus 5.5.
>> Hello. Hello, AIS Live. My
>> Oh my god, I'm so excited for this.
>> Let's Let's get some energy going in
here.
It's been a great two days.
Wow. Okay, that was my first time
watching that and I will say that that
is so so impressive. Like that almost
feels more impressive to me than when
Astra did that on its first try. So,
that was really, really good. I mean,
look at how it did the layering here.
And, you know, some of it felt a little
bit static, but the music, the sound
effects, the pacing, the way it came in
and out, all of this layering, I mean, I
thought that this was actually really,
really good. Like, definitely better
than I thought it was going to give me.
All right, now we will take a look at
Soul's version. This has been so
energizing.
Cloud code is my primary driver.
I can go to bed, come back, and it'll
still be working.
Okay. Um, I mean, it's still impressive,
but it does not give me the same energy.
It didn't have the same just like
fast-paced feel. it doesn't get me as
excited for the next event compared to
Opus' version. So Opus 5.5 definitely
wins that in my opinion. So Opus is two
for two right now. And you can see here
when it comes to time and pricing, Opus
was faster, 5 minutes faster, as well as
only double the cost. So even though
Opus was five bucks more expensive here,
I'm giving this one to Opus. Opus is 2
and 0 right now. And I'm so so glad that
we're actually seeing this because Opus
5 was really bad. Like I haven't used
Opus 5 in a long time. I was using 4.8 8
and Opus 5 was just so so bad. It was so
slow. But Opus 5.5 so far, I've really
really been enjoying it. So, I'm feeling
good about getting back a little bit
more usage on my cloud subscription now.
Um because I really do like both of
these harnesses and they've got
different good models. Like I do really
really love Astra, but Opus 5.5 for the
cost, I'm getting excited about it. But
anyways, let's move on to use case
number three. All right, so for use case
number three, we are doing an Instagram
reel. So I told it to use hyperframes. I
told it to edit it. I gave both models
the same footage and the same prompt.
Let's this time start with GBD6 souls
output. And I'm not going to play the
entire reel, but here we go. Stop
prompting Claude. Andre Karpathy thinks
there's a much better way to work with
AI. And his method has three layers.
Layer one is the spec. Instead of giving
Claude a task and hoping it understands
you, work with it to create a detailed
spec first. Have Claude interview you
about what you're actually trying to
achieve. Then break the work into
smaller checkpoints before it starts.
Layer two is the verifier. Before Claude
does anything, define exactly what a
good result looks like. Then give it
ways to actually check its own work.
whether that's another AI model or real
data or tests that it can run on its
own. Okay, not impressed at all. There's
a weird like humming noise in the
background. There's not really that many
engaging animations or there's no music
at all. I think that this is a very meh
output. Astra does a much better job
with editing reels and editing videos.
But this is just not something that I
would have put on my Instagram account
for real. I would have wanted to iterate
a lot more than just what we see here.
And now let's take a look at Opus 5.5's
version of this reel. Stop prompting
Claude. Andre Karpathy thinks there's a
much better way to work with AI. And his
method has three layers. Layer one is
the spec. Instead of giving Claude a
task and hoping it understands you, work
with it to create a detailed spec first.
Have Claude interview you about what
you're actually trying to achieve. Then
break the work into smaller checkpoints
before it starts. Layer two is the
verifier. Before Claude does anything,
define exactly what a good result looks
like. Then give it ways to actually
check its own work, whether that's
another AI model or real data or tests
that it can run on its own. Okay, that
was really good. Like, this is so much
better. It's more engaging. Look at
these like typing animations, the sound
effects you guys noticed. All of this
was more engaging. It's still not
something that I would probably put on
my Instagram, but this is like without a
shadow of a doubt significantly better
than what we just got from GBD6 Soul.
And this version was pretty interesting
with the pricing cost. It took double
the time with Opus 5.5 and like four
times the cost. But once again, in this
case, I would pay the premium there. The
question would be, okay, so Opus spent
11 bucks and Soul spent almost three
bucks. If we iterated with Soul over and
over to get to 11 bucks of spend, would
it be where Opus is or would it be
better? I think that's the interesting
question to sort of think about, but
also like you love the ability to just
oneshot stuff and they both use the same
skills. They both have the exact same
stuff. It seems like there's just more
potential over here with a lot of this
sort of like design and creative stuff
so far. So anyways, right now Opus is
three for three. So, we're heading into
the next experiment with Opus being up
30. So, let's go on to number four. All
right. So, in this example, I gave both
models a ton of data, like a ton of
data, and I said, "Hey, build me a
Google sheet analytics, and then build
me a dashboard as well." So, this was
Opus 5.5's Google Sheet. This one looks
pretty clean. You can see that we've got
these different boxes with different
metrics like AIR, MR, customers, you
know, gross margin. We have all these
stats. We have these visualizations
right here. We can move into a P&L. We
can move into SAS metrics with more
visualizations. We can see cash and
runway, unit economics, pricing,
headcount, go to market, pipeline, um
customers, and then some data notes as
well. I think that this looks pretty
well. It feels branded. We have, you
know, clearly some sort of color theme
with like black or a dark blue and
orange. And yeah, this looks pretty
good. We also got a pitch deck, which I
can open up right here. And you can see
that we have um like a logo has been
created. Once again, we have sort of
like that navy blue and dark blue or
sorry, navy blue and orange. What I
meant to say, we have a picture here.
We've got um this stuff is coming
through pretty simple, but also pretty
clean. We have more data visualizations,
some more B-roll or not B-roll, images
being generated. Um it's not too bad.
It's not too wordy, but it's not too
premium either. So, it's just all right.
And then it also created us an analytics
dashboard. We can see right here that we
have I mean this looks very vibe coded,
very AI generated, but hey, the
dashboard seems to be functional. It has
different ways for us to switch through.
This is obviously using the same data
that we saw on our um Google sheet that
it made for us earlier. I like this
highlighting effect. Um same down here.
So, not too bad of a dashboard. Oh, we
can also switch between different tabs
and switch between different modes as
well here. So, that's pretty cool. And
then the last thing you see that it
created for us here was a landing page
which is running locally. And we can see
we have an image here with different
like you know paper and clipboard things
flying around. These are on different
layers. So, that's a nice little scroll
animation. Here we've got a Monday
brief. We come down here into a little
bit of an animation with filling in some
gaps. Here we have more text coming in
dynamically. We've got a little scroll
animation here. So very clean. You can
tell it's obviously AI generated. It
just feels a little bit AI generated,
but hey, there's some nice animations in
here and some nice layering that
definitely gives it a little bit of an
edge. So anyways, that was Opus. Let's
go over to Soul and see what it was able
to do with all of this data. Okay, so we
have once again a PowerPoint, we have a
Google sheet, we have an analytics
dashboard and a client page. So let's
take a look real quick at the actual
slide deck. We can see that we have very
similar. Like I wouldn't say that
anything here is too different,
honestly. Like this looks almost exactly
the same as the one that Opus 5.5
generated for us. And you know what I'm
actually suspicious of? Is this the
exact same deck? This might be the exact
same one. They might have gotten
confused and gotten in each other's way
there and just like one of them grabbed
the other deck, which is pretty
interesting. M. Okay, so somehow along
the way, these two models started
working together. They probably started
to work inside of the same project
folder, and I didn't yet specify in this
example. I didn't say, "Hey, make sure
you're not overwriting any other agents
work." So, this is a really interesting
point. Like, I don't know exactly what
to do here. Um, I think they built
everything the exact same, which is
really, really interesting. They
literally created everything together.
And in this case, they both still spent
money. And Soul spent way more here,
actually. So, it it ran for 8 minutes
longer and it cost three bucks more. So,
this is honestly a little bit of a weird
one. I'm not going to like assign a
winner here, and I'm sorry if you guys
are like pissed off that I let them do
that in this in this specific example,
but they took a ton of data and they had
to build kind of a story out of it and
create four deliverables and they sort
of collaborated on that, which I thought
was interesting. Anyways, here's what we
got on the the cost and the runtime for
this specific example. Okay, guys, real
quick. In the moment of filming, I
didn't think anything too much of it,
but while I was editing, I was like,
"Wait a minute, that doesn't really make
sense." So, I went back to the session
and I did the math again, and I found
out that this actually was only codecs
$3.60
and about 9 minutes. So, the previous
figures, I was like, "Wait a minute,
that just doesn't really seem to add
up." So, at the end of this video, when
we're going over the total cost, just
subtract about 19 bucks from um GBD6
Soul's total cost. But everything else
was pretty consistent. Once again,
apologize for messing this one up. Um, I
should have put that in the prompt. I
normally do. Didn't really think to do
it for this one for some reason. But
either way,
I fixed it. And just to show you guys
what happened, I had both GBT Soul and
um, Opus inspect the logs on both sides
and they both agreed on what happened
here, which is really interesting.
Basically, I gave Claude the request and
it began creating files and then Codex
got the same request. obviously in the
same repo. But what happened is the
first time I sent this to Codeex, it
failed because like GBD6 Soul was still
rolling out and I was like, "Oh, I got
to get on these prompts." So it failed.
And then when I resumed it, what was
this 16 minutes later? Claude was
already like pretty far along the way
with building. So it basically just
grabbed all of the stuff that Claude was
working on and then started editing
those files on top while Claude was
still working. So, I truly think that
some of these deliverables would have
been better if maybe if Soul didn't get
in there and make some changes. But, you
know, obviously it's hard to say, but I
think that some of the stuff that looked
a little bit AI generated, I'm wondering
if maybe that's because Soul got in here
and made some changes. But, I do think
that the deck looks pretty good and I
think that this Google sheet does
overall look still pretty solid. So,
anyways, we're going to move on to the
next experiment, but I wanted to at
least show you guys like the order of
events there and what happened because I
think that actually is, you know, pretty
interesting. But anyways, moving on to
use case number five, we have this game.
So, we're going to first look at um GBT6
Souls version. It created a game called
Small Hours. I gave them the same prompt
obviously, and this thing is loading up
super slow. My computer down there also
started to get quite loud. So, this
thing must be a pretty large game. Okay,
so here it is. We basically will just be
walking around with WD, clicking to
interact, and mouse to look around. So,
I'll hit begin. We see the Ren Museum of
Miniatures closed for good at 6 o'clock
tonight. Everything your grandmother
built goes to auction in the morning.
You sat down in her reading chair to say
goodbye.
Okay, we got some sound effects coming
in.
Wow. Okay, so this is like really
telling me a story here. Okay, cool. So,
this is me able to look around, move
around. Honestly, not too bad from like
a design perspective. Although my mouse
if it goes out of frame, that's it. Like
my mouse isn't locked. You see my mouse
is nowhere. I'm moving my mouse around,
but like nothing's happening until I
bring it back into frame, which is a
problem because if I want to do a full
360, I can't. So, that's a little bit
weird. Little bit of an issue there. I'm
not even sure like how I'd go about
trying to fix that. But anyways, walking
around here. Okay. Click to interact.
Switch on the sewing room light. Uh,
right there. Right there.
Switch on the parents bedroom light. Oh,
that's just telling me what I can do.
Interesting.
>> Wow. I mean, this is honestly unplayable
because of this mouse thing. Like, I
can't I can't turn this way if I want to
because my mouse goes out of screen.
That's not good. But honestly, like as
far as the storyline goes and the way
this feels, like it feels smooth. It's
just this mouse issue, which honestly, I
can't even play this anymore because of
that. So, I'm going to have to stop.
We're gonna go over to Opus version. You
know what's awful is the exact same
thing happened here as what happened in
the previous version.
So they literally once again started
working on each other's files. And
obviously that's like a prompt error
because I didn't specify in these
prompts not to edit any other files.
Usually I do say that, but in this one I
just kind of was shooting off these
prompts. So unfortunately we'll have to
take the outputs here with a bit of a,
you know, a grain of salt because they
started working on the same thing. But I
don't think that this experiment is just
totally ruined because the pricing is
still really interesting to me because
somehow we still had Opus worked for two
and a half hours almost with Soul
working for an hour and Opus coming in
at four times more expensive. So
unfortunately guys, I'm sorry that that
happened. I mean we we have seen so far
that Opus does seem to be better when it
comes to actually giving us these sorts
of outputs, but I think it's important
to understand like where would the
handoff be between these two types of
models. All right. Well, okay. Well,
number six, these agents did not work on
the exact same deliverable. Thank
goodness. So, let's go ahead and launch
these up. Basically, what I had them do
is look through my past 100 YouTube
videos. I'll show you the prompt up
here. And I wanted them to create me
basically a 3D playable world explaining
all these concepts from YouTube. I
thought this was interesting to see how
they reasoned about this and how they
thought about telling a story out of
this. So, let's open these up and take a
look. Okay, so this one is Opus' output.
We'll go ahead and start exploring. We
can see that we walk forward with W. Can
we Okay, we can move like this. So,
we've got kind of this cartoon 3D world
where we're able to walk inside and take
a look.
I can sprint with space. This is our
guide. We can talk to Nova
>> building.
>> Okay, cool. I also can throw these balls
for some reason.
I can grab a ball and I can throw it.
Okay, cool.
So we can see we can come into here how
AI thinks and we have sort of like an
interactive world where we can look at
tokens. You can see AI reads word
pieces. We can look at things like the
model harness and we can press E to
learn.
>> So basically I can come to all of these
little dashboards and I can ask how it
works. We also see that there's some
sort of game here.
Use the next word machine.
the cat sat on the
interesting. Okay. So, it's like I'm
dropping balls in here to see like
almost like how it chooses the next
word. The way that an LLM generates the
next word. So, there's obviously a bit
of an issue up there because um the
balls were getting stuck. Probably
because I dropped so many at once. But
that is kind of cool. It's a cool like
little simulation of how this should
work except for the balls are getting
stuck too often. But anyways, nice
little interactive way to explain these
concepts. So, I'm not obviously going to
go into every single one of these rooms,
but there's quite a few. Right here, we
have the context window, and all of
these have the same sort of explainers,
but they all seem to have some sort of
game as well. You can see I can add
blocks, and I can like see how a context
window fills up, which is pretty cool.
So, like, we're getting these
interactive experiences as we're
learning more about different concepts.
So, I'm not going to go into a ton of
these, like I said, we have agent arena,
we have prompt power, team of helpers,
skills workshop. Let's actually head
into the skills workshop real quick and
see what the game is here. It's a recipe
robot. So, we basically build a tower.
Um, I'm not really controlling anything
here, so that's getting boring. But
anyways, this is pretty cool how it was
able to go through create this 3D world
for us, and we have all of these
different concepts. Memory, automation,
building, model garage.
Anyways, that's not too bad of an
output. And now we'll open up the idea
atlas from Soul. You can see this one's
a little bit different vibe. Obviously,
not as realistic at all with the way
that you move around and you can just
like walk through the fountain, but
similar sort of feel. We have real world
results. We'll pop into here real quick.
Um, also I can't get rid of this overlay
for some reason, which is kind of
annoying. Um, like this is just way too
crowded, I would say, of an interface.
We can come in here for ideas,
bottleneck, outcome, baseline, delivery.
I think in here we can make maybe read
uh it's not letting me read these
things. Click to read. How to help.
Okay. I would click with my mouse rather
than like interacting with um E. But
anyways, this one doesn't obviously feel
as good. Like this would be harder to
spend I don't know some time in. Like
the other one I think I could have sat
in there for maybe 15 minutes and before
I got bored. But in here I'm like
already a little bit over this. It's a
little bit overwhelming. It just doesn't
feel as real. And this is where you can
see sort of like the design and realism
come into play. So like earlier that
previous example where we were in that
museum, that was definitely Opus kind of
like carrying the load there. That was
definitely Opus making most of that code
and designing most of that actual game.
So anyways, this one's going to go to
Opus 5.5 as well. And now look at the
cost on this one. For Opus, this was an
hour and 45 minutes. For Soul, this was
about 50 minutes and Opus was 60 bucks,
whereas Soul was $8.55.
So I'm going to give this one to Opus.
Even though it was way more expensive,
the outputs are just coming back way
better. I'm just I'm pretty impressed by
Opus so far. All right, so this next one
we're going to start with Soul. It's
pretty interesting. I said I wanted to
take a trip from October 1st to the
30th. I want to go to super cool AI
events. I want to see cool nature. I'm
in Chicago. I want to also get out of
the country. And I just basically gave
it this really vague idea and said that
I wanted to turn my itinerary into this
3D world that I can explore. So I was
really trying to see what they could do
with like building experiences from, you
know, pretty vague ideas. And you'll see
right here that it asked me a question.
And that is one thing that I did notice
about Soul more often is that it
actually stopped and asked you questions
a lot more than Opus 5.5. Some people
might say that's good. Some people might
say that's bad. I personally love when
they stop to ask questions because it
means that they're really trying to
understand what I want. But sometimes
when you do things like a SLG goal,
maybe you don't want it to ask you a
question because you want it to keep
going. So usually though with what I've
noticed with Codeex is when it stops ask
you a question, it doesn't actually
stop. It'll inject a question into the
chat, but if you don't answer it, it'll
still keep going. So, I do really like
the way that Soul asks questions. So,
anyways, here is the output we got from
Soul. We have 30 days, one orbit. We
just have this kind of globe. So, I'm
not sure I'm not really getting the 3D
experience I was hoping to get, but I
wasn't too specific. So, anyways, this
is what we see here. Um, we can see
we're going to start from Chicago to San
Francisco. It's giving me a link right
here. This is going to kayak.com. So,
it's going to a flight. It seems like
this one is going to the Hyatt Regency
in San Francisco. So, it's providing me
all these links, which I did ask for. I
asked for all of the links. We can see
the the order is San Francisco, Yusede,
Amsterdam. Not going to say that. That's
an Iceland. I don't know how to
pronounce these things. South Coast,
Toronto, Aangquin, Niagara Falls, Vegas,
Zion, Bryce Canyon, Grand Canyon, Red
Rock Canyon. We have the entire plan
here. And all of these looks like it
links me back to one of the places on
the actual 3D globe, which I'm able to
click in, and it basically like pulls up
the little itinerary for that day. And
all of these have links that I could go
book things or um grab tickets or
whatever it is. So, it's really not too
bad for a simple itinerary. It seems to
have thought through a lot and planned a
lot of stuff out. So, it's not too bad.
But, I wish the 3D globe experience was
better. And here we have Claude Codes
version with Opus. This one, honestly,
very similar, although the map seems to
be better. It's also numbered here. So,
I can click in. Okay, this is definitely
more of what I was looking for when I
said I wanted like the globe and for it
to be interactive. And you can see that
if I'm going to these different stops,
actually not there. Here it's actually
taking me more inside of what I'm
actually doing and where I'm going. This
is definitely more of what I was looking
for. Um they're planning out very
similar things. You can see the order is
a bit different. But this one had San
Francisco Tech Week, which is something
that I was hoping it would actually
include. This is like the 9th through um
I don't know, a few days later. But this
one, I'm not sure if it actually
included San Francisco Tech Week. Yeah,
this one had us in San Francisco right
at the beginning of the month and there
wasn't any sort of big event here. It
was literally just going to San
Francisco. So, this one did better
research that I would have trusted more
for saying, "Hey, I want to go to cool
AI events throughout the month of
October." This one definitely was doing
better. Um, it also picked out some
other AI events in San Jose. And then
just the experience of this interface,
besides the loading of the globe being
pretty slow, the experience here is
significantly better. So, this is going
to sound repetitive. I think overall
Opus is just a much better model. I
think that it was also like I don't
know. I feel like GBD 5.6 Soul was much
better than Opus 5, but Opus 5.5 is now
much better than GBT6 Soul. They ran for
basically the same amount of time and
Opus 5.5 here was three times the cost
of Soul. But here's one that's really,
really, really, really interesting to
me. I'm I'm starting with the pricing
just to show you how interesting this
one is. So, this was a codebase. I had
Astro design this experiment and I kept
this all neutral at the beginning. So it
didn't know it was judging an open eye
model versus a cloud model, but I had it
designed this experiment with a massive
codebase and then had to actually make
them like fix it and analyze stuff and
and repair stuff. And what came back was
that Soul did did better. Soul got 100
out of 100 whereas Opus got 97 out of
100 and passed all 30 checks whereas
Opus missed one of them. And what else
is interesting about this is not only
did Opus cost basically 20 times more
and was two times slower, but Soul
actually stopped halfway through because
of some sort of security thing. Like it
wouldn't let me continue on. So I had to
pause both of them and then I had to
tell Asher what happened. And then Asher
said, "Okay, let's switch it up a little
bit and then send this prompt back to
both of them." But Opus didn't stop.
Soul stopped because of some sort of
cyber security thing and safety thing.
But Opus didn't. And I just wanted to
call that out cuz I thought that was
really interesting. But what ended up
happening was Soul somehow ran for $1 on
this massive codebase and did better.
And so I think like it's really
interesting to see how different these
models are and where they excel because
with a lot of these quick tasks or a lot
of these more code I don't want to say
code writing tasks but maybe like code
reviewing and execution and repairing
soul has been really good. But then we
also saw something like at the beginning
of this video where it missed one of my
Fireflies transcripts where I said nit
and it just gave me the wrong answer. So
obviously one test like this isn't
definitive, but in this case, you know,
Soul actually does come out on top. And
I would say by a wide margin, you know,
for 120th of the cost and getting better
output, that's pretty good. All right,
so these last two, 9 and 10, have to do
with browser use. And this one's very
interesting to me because historically,
Codeex with pretty much whatever model
has almost always beat Cloud Code with
whatever model when it came to browser
use. And I've loved Codeex for browser
use. So let's see how this one goes. I
basically gave them both the same
prompt. I gave them a course structure
with the videos and descriptions and
everything and I told them to make the
course inside of my free school AIS. So
in here, here's the classroom. You can
see if I scroll down and I give this a
refresh real quick, we should see we
have two new classrooms in here. We have
the sole AIOS and the Opus AOS. Let's
click into Soul, we can see that it
uploaded all the videos. They're all
labeled as drafts 1 through 15. Each
video has the description, key points,
key quotes, resources, and as I flick
through, we can see that all of them
hopefully are uploaded correctly. It
seems like it's got all of these right
and we have properly linked, you know,
documentation or resources and skills
and they're all named. They're all
linked. So, this looks pretty good. I
don't think we're going to notice
anything significantly different from
these two except for maybe like the cost
and time. So, let's look at the opus
one. We can see, okay, the only
difference here is that it didn't make
each page as a draft. It just made the
overall course as a draft, which
honestly I think is a little bit
smarter. But anyways, um introduction,
mindset, all of these have the same
description, key points, the same things
are um linked. Although this one linked
it here, but also linked it here. It
duplicated some work. It linked things
twice, which isn't as good, right? Like
I don't want it to link everything
twice. That just doesn't really make too
much sense. But besides that, nothing
really to pick on here with this course.
And I was expecting Soul to come in and
be cheaper here. But in this case, Opus
5.5 was faster and cheaper and it had
that tiny little mess up. So in this
case, I would be giving this one to Opus
because the results were basically the
same. Opus also didn't make each
individual page a draft, which I thought
was a nice touch and it was cheaper and
faster. So Opus and Cloud Code have
actually won a browser use use case,
which I haven't seen them do in my
experience with Cloud Code versus Codex
in a while. So let's move on to number
10, which is the last one. It's also
another browser use case. Okay, so this
use case is slowly becoming one of my
favorite like benchmark tests with new
models. I gave them a reference image,
which I'll pull up real quick. It was
this image right here. This was an AI
generated image of me and Adam Sandler.
And basically what I told them to do was
I told them to open up Canva and use
like the drawing and painting tools to
recreate this. And look what Opus 5.5
gave us. That is actually a really
really good output. Like I wasn't
expecting it to be this good because
when I've done this in the past, even
with models like Fable, we got something
back that was horrible. And this is
actually better than Astra's output that
it gave me when I did this a few weeks
ago. And then when I gave this to Soul,
first of all, it just tried to create an
image. And I was like, "Okay, that's
cheating. That's not what I wanted you
to do." So I had it like I just do did
it again. I gave it another prompt, but
it ended up giving me this output. And I
was like, "Okay, um I'm wondering if
maybe it just needs to try again because
the first time it it made an image. So I
let it have another try. I spun up
another session and I told it to do it
again." And then it gave me this type of
output again, which is just comically
bad. So I'm not exactly sure what
happened in the degradation from GBD6
Astra to GBD6 Soul with browser use and
with this Canva test, but this is just
horrific. And obviously like we don't
even have to debate that Cloud Code is
going to take this one as well. Opus 5.5
has just really really impressed me so
far. And yeah, um you can take a look at
the speed and cost here as well. Opus
was slower, you know, 30 minutes slower
and about four times more expensive, but
the output is just so much better. So,
this is where we're at after all of
those experiments. You can see that we
had 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 wins for Opus 5.5 and
one win for Soul and then two that just
like didn't count because I guess I
messed up. That was definitely my fault.
So, 7 to one OBS 5.5. What about the
total stats here? Well, OPUS 5.5 was 8
minutes or sorry, 8 hours and 40 minutes
across all of the experiments. Soul was
5 hours and 51 minutes across all the
experiments. So, OPUS was a little bit
slower and also cost about three times
as much at 213 bucks compared to Soul's
$74.46.
So, once again, we kind of came into
this experiment understanding that Opus
is um a bigger model. It's a little bit
bigger, a little bit more expensive, and
my gut was telling me that okay, I think
Opus 5.5 might be a little bit better
than Soul based on the pricing. Um, but
but 5.6 Soul was really good and Opus 5
was really bad. So, it's a big jump here
and I'm really excited to see what's
going to come next from Enthropic with
maybe their next Fable model or
something because they're obviously
they've been really grinding on the
feedback that they've been getting on X
and just like their internal use and
everything. Um, and I'm honestly a
little bit disappointed in Soul. It
feels more like this is a GPT6
Luna or Terra. Like this doesn't feel I
don't know. 5.6 Soul is really good. I
thought that GBT6 soul was going to be
better. I do like how the pricing is is
really cheap. That was like exciting,
but now we know why it's so much
cheaper. So anyways guys, to sort of
wrap this up into as concise of one
sentence as I can try to make, I would
say Obus 5.5 is a major step up from
Obus 5. GBD6 Soul is a step down from
5.6 Soul. It feels more like a GBD6 Luna
that might come out. I would trust
Claude Opus more for creativity and for
some judgment calls and I would maybe
want to defer some work to GBD6 Astra if
I know very very specifically what I
want and I just want them to execute
step one, step two, step three, step
four. I think a pretty cool scenario
would be using Opus 5.5 as the
orchestrator that spins up and sends off
very specific instructions to a bunch of
little GBD6 soul workers. What I think
is very cool is that Opus 5.5 and GBD6
Soul are both cheaper than their
predecessors with Opus 5 and with GBD6
or sorry, GBD 5.6. I'm about to lose my
mind here. I've been up all day. Um,
it's late and I have just like 5.5, 6,
5.6, just all these little numbers in my
head, so forgive me, but that's kind of
how I feel. Anyways, that's going to do
it for this one. If you guys enjoyed,
you learned something new, please give
it a like. It helps me out a ton. And as
always, I appreciate you guys making it
to the end of the video, and I'll see
you all in the next one. Thanks
everyone.